{
  "meta": {
    "learningGoals": "<par>In this skill you learn to <term>solve a linear equation that has fractions</term> with the unknown in the denominator. For an equation like <inline-math/> you will be able to find the solution <inline-math/>. This includes <skill-link>moving equation factors</skill-link> to get <inline-math/> out of any denominator, and subsequently <skill-link>solving the resulting linear equation</skill-link> in the default way. Effectively, this allows the solution of any type of linear equation.</par>"
  },
  "theory": {
    "intro": "<par>We may run into equations where the unknown is in the denominator of a fraction. Think of for instance <inline-math/>. Sometimes these equations are actually <term>linear equations in disguise</term>. Here we learn how to check that, and how to subsequently solve such equations.</par>",
    "cleaning": "<head>Cleaning up the equation</head><par>As usual with equations, we first clean them up. In the equation <inline-math/> we see that the unknown <inline-math/> is in the denominator, which is inconvenient. To fix this, we <skill-link>move the factor <inline-math/> to the other side</skill-link> to get <block-math/> Identically, we move the factor <inline-math/> to the other side to get <block-math/> Now <inline-math/> is not in any denominator anymore, and if we study our result, we see that we wound up with a linear equation!</par>",
    "solving": "<head>Solving the linear equation</head><par>We can now <skill-link>solve the linear equation</skill-link> in the standard way. Expanding brackets gives <block-math/> Bringing all terms with <inline-math/> to the left and all other terms to the right, we wind up with <block-math/> Merging similar terms directly simplifies this to <block-math/> Moving the factor <inline-math/> to the other side gives us the solution <block-math/> As a check, we insert this into the original equation and get <block-math/> With some work, we can see that both sides reduce to <inline-math/>, which matches. The solution is correct.</par>",
    "steps": "<head>The steps</head><par>To solve a linear equation in disguise, like <inline-math/>, take the following steps.</par><list><item><a>Whenever the unknown is in any fraction denominator, <skill-link>move this denominator (as factor) to the other side of the equation</skill-link> to fix this. For the example we do this twice to get <inline-math/>.</a></item><item><b>If the equation that comes out is a linear equation, then <skill-link>solve it</skill-link> in the default way. For the example, we indeed get a linear equation, whose solution can be found as <inline-math/>.</b></item></list>"
  },
  "practice": {
    "twoFractionsWithNumber": {
      "mainProblem": "Consider the equation <block-math/> Solve this equation for <inline-math/> and simplify the result as much as possible.",
      "step1": {
        "problem": "Move both the factor <inline-math/> and the factor <inline-math/> to the other side to ensure there is no <inline-math/> in any denominator anymore.",
        "solution": "The factor <inline-math/> appears on the right as a multiplication, and similarly the factor <inline-math/> appears on the left as a multiplication. This turns the equation into <block-math/>"
      },
      "step2": {
        "problem": "Solve the resulting equation for <inline-math/>.",
        "solution": "<par>As usual when solving a linear equation, we first expand brackets. This turns the equation into <block-math/> Moving everything with <inline-math/> to the left and everything without <inline-math/> to the right gives <block-math/> Merging terms to clean up the equation reduces it to <block-math/><check><on-true>Dividing by <inline-math/> gives us the solution <block-math/><check><on-true>This can still be simplified into <block-math/></on-true><on-false>This cannot be simplified further.</on-false></check></on-true><on-false>Coincidentally the factor before the <inline-math/> has already dropped out, so we have already found the solution, <block-math/></on-false></check></par><par>The last thing to do is to check the solution. Inserting it into the original equation gives <block-math/> Both sides reduce to <inline-math/> which shows that the solution is correct.</par>"
      },
      "step3": {
        "problem": "Clean up both equation sides separately by merging terms together.",
        "solution": "On the left we merge terms with <inline-math/> together, and on the right we simply add together the numbers. This results in <block-math/>"
      },
      "step4": {
        "problem": "Solve the resulting equation for <inline-math/>.",
        "solution": "<par><check><on-true>As usual when solving a product equation, we move the factor in front of <inline-math/> (here <inline-math/>) to the other side, where it will be divided by. This gives the solution <block-math/><check><on-true>This can still be simplified into <block-math/></on-true><on-false>This cannot be simplified further.</on-false></check></on-true><on-false>Coincidentally the factor before the <inline-math/> has already dropped out. As a result, we have already found the solution, <block-math/></on-false></check></par><par>The last thing to do is to check the solution. Inserting it into the original equation gives <block-math/> Both sides reduce to <inline-math/> which shows that the solution is correct.</par>"
      }
    },
    "oneFractionWithVariable": {
      "mainProblem": "Consider the equation <block-math/> Solve this equation for <inline-math/> and simplify the result as much as possible.",
      "step1": {
        "problem": "Move the factor <inline-math/> to the other side to ensure there is no <inline-math/> in any denominator anymore.",
        "solution": "The factor <inline-math/> appears on the <check><on-true>left</on-true><on-false>right</on-false></check> as a multiplication. This turns the equation into <block-math/>"
      },
      "step2": {
        "problem": "Solve the resulting equation for <inline-math/>.",
        "solution": "<par>As usual when solving a linear equation, we first expand brackets. This turns the equation into <block-math/> Moving everything with <inline-math/> to the left and everything without <inline-math/> to the right gives <block-math/> Merging terms to clean up the equation reduces it to <block-math/><check><on-true>Dividing by <inline-math/> gives us the solution <block-math/><check><on-true>This can still be simplified into <block-math/></on-true><on-false>This cannot be simplified further.</on-false></check></on-true><on-false>Coincidentally the factor before the <inline-math/> has already dropped out, so we have already found the solution, <block-math/></on-false></check></par><par>The last thing to do is to check the solution. Inserting it into the original equation gives <block-math/> Both sides reduce to <inline-math/> which shows that the solution is correct.</par>"
      }
    },
    "oneFractionWithNumber": {
      "mainProblem": "Consider the equation <block-math/> Solve this equation for <inline-math/> and simplify the result as much as possible.",
      "step1": {
        "problem": "Before starting, simplify the equation a bit by bringing the <inline-math/> to the other side and merging numbers together.",
        "solution": "By bringing the <inline-math/> to the <check><on-true>left</on-true><on-false>right</on-false></check> and <check><on-true>subtracting it from</on-true><on-false>adding it to</on-false></check> the <inline-math/>, we get <block-math/>"
      },
      "step2": {
        "problem": "Move the factor <inline-math/> to the other side to ensure there is no <inline-math/> in any denominator anymore.",
        "solution": "The factor <inline-math/> appears on the <check><on-true>left</on-true><on-false>right</on-false></check> as a multiplication. This turns the equation into <block-math/>"
      },
      "step3": {
        "problem": "Solve the resulting equation for <inline-math/>.",
        "solution": "<par>As usual when solving a linear equation, we first expand brackets. This turns the equation into <block-math/> The only term with <inline-math/> is already on the <check><on-true>left</on-true><on-false>right</on-false></check> so we can keep it there. Moving all numbers to the <check><on-true>right</on-true><on-false>left</on-false></check> and pulling them together results in <block-math/><check><on-true>Dividing by <inline-math/> gives us the solution <block-math/><check><on-true>This can still be simplified into <block-math/></on-true><on-false>This cannot be simplified further.</on-false></check></on-true><on-false>Coincidentally the factor before the <inline-math/> has already dropped out, so we have already found the solution, <block-math/></on-false></check></par><par>The last thing to do is to check the solution. Inserting it into the original equation gives <block-math/> Both sides reduce to <inline-math/> which shows that the solution is correct.</par>"
      }
    },
    "twoFractionsWithVariable": {
      "mainProblem": "Consider the equation <block-math/> Solve this equation for <inline-math/> and simplify the result as much as possible.",
      "step1": {
        "problem": "Move both the factor <inline-math/> and the factor <inline-math/> to the other side to ensure there is no <inline-math/> in any denominator anymore.",
        "solution": "The factor <inline-math/> appears on the right as a multiplication, and similarly the factor <inline-math/> appears on the left as a multiplication. This turns the equation into <block-math/>"
      },
      "step2": {
        "problem": "Expand the double brackets on both sides to make sure there are no brackets left.",
        "solution": "To get rid of the double brackets, we multiply each term from the left brackets separately with each term from the right brackets. And we do this for both sides. Out comes <block-math/>"
      },
      "step3": {
        "problem": "Note that the term <inline-math/> cancels on both sides of the equation. Solve the remaining equation for <inline-math/>.",
        "solution": "<par>We follow the default approach. Moving everything with <inline-math/> to the left and everything without <inline-math/> to the right gives <block-math/> Merging terms to clean up the equation reduces it to <block-math/><check><on-true>Dividing by <inline-math/> gives us the solution <block-math/><check><on-true>This can still be simplified into <block-math/></on-true><on-false>This cannot be simplified further.</on-false></check></on-true><on-false>Coincidentally the factor before the <inline-math/> has already dropped out, so we have already found the solution, <block-math/></on-false></check></par><par>The last thing to do is to check the solution. Inserting it into the original equation gives <block-math/> Both sides reduce to <inline-math/> which shows that the solution is correct.</par>"
      }
    }
  }
}